Right. So my name is Thomas. I'm going
to talk to you about scaling AI adoption
from 30 engineers to take away
transformation. Uh so first of all who
am I? So I'm a AI platform public
manager at uh so
I think you all know what it is but if
you don't so it's an online booking
platform for patients to book their
appointments with their practitioners
and we are present in all Europe.
Um so I'm going to talk to you about how
we managed to have uh the scale of uh
starting with 30 engineers to have uh
600 engineers in the end using AI
tooling. Um but just a few numbers uh as
to where we are right now. So as I
mentioned the club has 600 engineers. We
do have at the moment 60% of them who
are daily active users of AI. So we do
leverage those tools uh very much and
those tools are cloud code and github
and if we look if we zoom out a bit in
terms of weekly ex user we are at 75% to
80% so we are very much invested into uh
using AI uh into our tech
how it started uh so back in uh May uh
we had a single pace with 30 engineers.
Uh it came from action that was both
productive and active because both our
leadership team uh was very interested
in uh basically achieving productivity
gain thanks to the AI tools and as well
as the proactive reaction because some
of our engineers were already
have had already started using AI on
their end which created kind of a shadow
it inside the which is not which was not
something that we wanted to
Um
I'm skipping the the pilot phase but
after the pilot phase uh start landing
for a month uh we had like pretty
positive feedback from the 30 engineers.
So we decided to expand the pilot and
start uh the beginning of Q3 so
beginning of Q to have all our engineers
uh leveraging those tools. So we gave
them a license for all the tools and
starting the experiment with them as a
glo experiment for the home tech company
during a quarter. So we have it with
having a single goal having all of them
use AI on a daily basis basically
adoption that's our uh main focus and
the focus we we've had during this whole
quarter. Uh and why uh because as of
right now agent coding is still
relatively new and we're still
discovering uh use cases on a daily
basis on a weekly basis and we wanted to
highlight uh the experimentation and
learning all together first so that we
later on could
basically scale and maximize the impact
of those AI tools.
Just a a quick uh a quick note before I
did dive into the presentation. So as I
mentioned I'm a platform product manager
uh working on tech topics. Uh so as a
first approach to try to increase the
adoption um we basically treat our
engineers as first class customer and it
means that it means that we have uh
interviewed them a lot hearing their
complaints hearing their pain points and
what about what I'm about to share to
you tonight is the first and major pain
point of adoption u in our engineering
team among the 600 engineers and that's
what I'm going to present to you and
different actions that we took to
basically try to uh have them become
adopters.
So the first fiction point uh the
friction point was about quality and
reliability and basically the engineers
were afraid that uh the code generated
by those tools
would be basically poor. So it would be
back code and something that was not
going to be shipped into production and
sometimes they even felt that um the the
output of those LM through the the code
etc were not really actionable. So to
address those uh a few actions were
taken the first one was making sure that
first of all uh all the new joiners at
Dr. would get a proper uh training at
first
while joining the company so they can
get up to speed with our recommendation.
In the recommendation, we basically
created a whole documentation space for
them. Uh which has a ton of different
information in terms of best practices.
So how do I use um cloud code or
whatever to write unit test? How do I
use those for catching documentation?
How could I integrate uh react query V4
to V5? For example, like a set of
guidelines uh and best practices, but
also pitfalls like the Copy of LMS for
example like the LMS being too kind
every time to the to the engineers. uh
so we try to highlight those and uh and
to have like a proper documentation
space that they can consult and they
they can act on.
Second friction point uh was the lack of
confidence or knowledge uh basically. So
I have a new tool. I have access to
three new tools actually. Uh what should
I do with them basically? Uh so there
was first a low confidence in usage. uh
it was difficult for them to determine
how they could apply the LM magic let's
say to our code base and there was also
like in the end like a poor awareness of
the already existing use cases that some
engineers already found and developed
along the way. So uh few actions there.
Uh first of all we we created what what
we called an AI camp which is like a
which was like a week of trainings for
the whole engineering team during the
summer at the beginning of July. uh and
one of the few session during the the IT
camp where basically one-on-one hands-on
session where uh senior senior software
engineers would basically uh do some
hands-on session with all engineers like
in close groups like 10 to 15 people and
have them use and have them set up uh
those tools correctly. On top of this
and to highlight the the the different
use cases and the success stories inside
the company, we created like a weekly
digest like a Slack message, an email
like on different channels of
communication. A weekly digest where we
would highlight and share the success
stories of specific teams to all other
teams so that we make sure that the
learning of some were used by others.
Going on to the self friction point uh
talking about job security and
ideological barrier which was a very
heavy topic at the beginning. So
basically being afraid of being replaced
by a machine if I may say and the the
gist of the ideological resistance
toward having a machine breaking code.
So to actually address those uh two key
actions were taken uh during the day
camp once again uh we invited someone
from Google VM who actually presents
what LMS are and how do they work what
is a token how do works with token and
it basically gave a gist of um okay it's
not magic there's actually tech behind
it and it demystified like the the the
airlines in general and it help all
software engineers understand better
what they were working with
and also um uh to address the this fear
of replacement by AI uh we wrote
a a vision document which we called uh
the AI augmented engineer vision which
is a document describing uh how we
believe adaptively AI should be used and
how it should power engineers and that
should replace Because in the end we
believe that there is a strong
opportunity to leverage those and that
it will basically enhance the
development of all engineers and it's
the the the next milestone in the tech
industry that we need to uh to embrace
and we wrote this document and it was uh
co-written uh with our CTO and with and
it was also shared during the the camp
that I that I mentioned
going on to the fourth friction point.
Uh the cost and un environmental concern
which was a a huge one as well. uh the
underlying concerns were well I might
use those but uh how am I going to
impact uh the company in terms of cost
because if you are using some models for
example focus on ongo which is very
expensive um in terms of med per token
in terms of dollar per million token uh
you could indeed create a huge bill at
the end and the second one was like the
ecological impact
using LLM would require computational
power inside data center which would in
the end uh create carbon footprint. So
to address the first one in terms of
cost, uh we had a a backup of our
leadership team to emphasize the the the
thing that we wanted the whole tech
organization at the field to actually
experiment, discover, learn new use case
use cases, share those with others and
try to build upon those uh learnings.
And the second one was about about the
ecological impact. It's it's about
actually it's not the the most easiest
one to answer because there's no real
big papers available yet on the carbon
footprint emitted by those LMS. Um but
we are trying to like contextualize the
the usage of those LM inside the global
scheme of everything. Like if an LLM
allows you for example to save like a
let's say a few hours of work because it
it created code for you maybe it saved
you a bit of electricity as well and
such. Um but this is not something uh
really easy to measure. So we're showing
also other alternatives for example the
local usage of LMS like having and such
to have actually run some local models
like recently like OpenAI released
GPOSS with 20 billion parameters which
is great to actually work in local so
we're trying to leverage those on
specific use cases and limiting the LLM
usage running into data centers
And the uh the fifth friction points uh
was about barriers. Um okay, I'm having
trouble getting license or and also like
the lack of time like hey yes you're
asking me to experiment but I don't have
time. I have a road map to to follow and
I have projects uh and deadlines with
them. to address those um we made sure
to have a clear on boarding channel uh
with a recommendation like some software
engineers were more inclined to have
like a CLI approach like using neo for
example but some others were leveraging
jet brains ID for example which are very
heavy uh so we made sure that based on
their current usage of their ID we were
proposing the right tools for them uh
and we made sure that to have like a
proper
map and to for them in our documentation
so that they can follow this map and not
request the program tool.
Uh and the last one the lack of time we
made sure that uh they would not lack
any time to experiment because every
engineer at DI is actually having
personal objective every quarter and
we've requested every engineering
manager at the to set personal objective
of their engineers. So like 10 to 20% of
their times spent purely on
experimenting uh with one of those tools
and reporting their feedback basically.
So we make sure that it was included in
their time.
So that was about the the the main
friction points. Uh but where is our
current focus? So as I mentioned first
was adoption. Now we are trying to
maximize the impact and measuring the
impact as well. Um because there's one
thing that I like to say is like if we
if we are producing twice as many
requests compared to three months ago,
it means that we double our
productivity, right? Well, no, because
we might as well have doubled the number
of bugs as well, for example. So yeah,
doubling the the number of requests
alone doesn't mean anything. So we are
trying to have like an understanding of
like our engineering inputs like for
example the number of PRs the number of
line of code some of the data metrics as
well like the deployment frequency the
lead time to change but as well looking
at those with a control with a set of
control KPIs like how many bugs did we
introduce this week how many incidents
we created uh how's our change failure
like for example so that's that was our
first initial um thinking of how we were
going to measure the impact.
After this uh we realized during the
summer that industry was basically
evolving on on this very very topic and
this is not like a paid promotion or
whatsoever but we we found the the a
framework made by a company called DX uh
which proposes actually
three three layer framework to actually
measure the the productivity increase or
not from AI tools uh and it's de
composed into three different layers.
The first related to adoption, the
second one is about AI impact metrics
and the third one is about how we
impacted your business. I recommend you
to actually check them out. It's pretty
interesting.
Um so that's our current focus. But
what's coming next? Um well in the end
uh we we found that uh our initiatives
and all our task that are meant toward
the AI AI tooling adoption was very much
focused on uh the coding part itself but
by it means that as of right now we do
are we are actually producing more P
request. So actually producing more more
p requests sorry uh produces as well
like an increase of uh p request review.
So people are engineers are asked to uh
review more PR on a daily basis. Um it
also uh creates a new bottleneck where
if we are producing more in terms of
just engineering output it means that
stories might also become a bottleneck
because there the stories are taken more
uh rapidly and it also puts other
bottlenecks like on the deployment
processes of everything because means
that if we are producing more PR we can
we could deploy more frequently so we
need more process on And just to to to
provide a quick feedback of what we
discover is that just by putting our
efforts toward coding. Well, in the end
it resulted in other bottlenecks that we
are still discovering as of today and we
are uh globally thinking on how do we
approach uh those AI tools and how do we
have like an AI culture in general so
that we can answer all those um all
those new bottlenecks that are emerging
in the software development life cycle.
[Applause]
questions.
>> I don't think I have the other mic. So,
Um, it's really interesting what you've
done. It's a bit crazy. Last time I came
to one of these things, we're talking
about how cool these things could be.
And now dog deliver it's got 600 users.
you um out of all those stats, the one
that really jumps out to me as
interesting is lead time to
but uh you know from idea to delivery.
>> Yeah.
>> I was wondering um yeah if you uh you
know you agree that that one's
interesting or that there's another one
that's particularly interesting to you
or whether it's too early to tell as
well. Just I don't want to put you on
the spot too much about
that. Um well looking at dollar metrics
in in general I would say is a great
thing because it's like standard of the
industry I won't be able yet to tell you
how it impacted us because we are in the
very making of actually applying those
frameworks to our own metrics to our own
feedback so I couldn't tell you but
definitely
I would say like have a look at
Dormetrix and uh industry becoming
standards I would say like the X for
example
it would give you an idea of where where
you're going at least is going in the
right direction or not but so far it's a
bit too early for us I'm sorry
question
>> one more and then
>> thank you for the great talk um one uh
part that got me interested. You you
said that you were adopting or even like
you were interviewing uh developers what
kind of tools they were using heavy and
unheavy. Um I personally have seen uh uh
myself but also with others that people
are tending to use more and more
lightweight developer frameworks uh with
something like cloud code or something
in the back that that kind of like
shifts more to lightweight. And I was
wondering if you've seen something
similar of of folks transitioning from
big idees to to more lightweight new or
code algorithms.
>> Um so uh in terms of tooling usage I
would say yes like for example at the
beginning the leading tool in terms of
adoption was a very ak
the leading AI tool nowadays is cloud
code. And most of our engineers are
nowadays users of code and if they are
still using Kar they might as well have
like a code license in Zen but
uh in terms of pure ID um we still have
a heavy uh user base of Jet Brains ID
for example mostly because it's tied to
their languages that they are writing
like Jaba based the application cotling
and such and we do did not have yet
of those licenses.
Thanks
[Applause]